Avoiding failure is not the same as
achieving success.
I hope these wishes come true for you as
it has for me.
My first wish to you
is that I wish you find joy in your
work. My second wish for you is to learn
to embrace failure. My last wish to you
is
Well, starting tomorrow
work is the rest of your life.
That's right.
>> [laughter]
>> Ouch.
Exactly.
So, my first wish is for you to find joy
in work. Find work that gives you great
joy, or just fall in love with whatever
work you do.
That's the only way you're going to do
your best work. That's the only way
you're going to do exquisite work.
Instead of working for a living,
think of it as your life's work.
I wish for you to love your work as much
as I've loved my work. Lori,
my kids, my family, the nearly 6,000
employees at Nvidia, and everybody I've
ever I've ever worked with in the
computer industry knows I love my work.
Nvidia is my life's work.
One that I'm passionate about, and one
that I'm giving my very best to make as
great as possible.
So, my first wish to you
is the same. That I wish you find joy in
your work. My second wish for you is to
learn to embrace failure.
I've just said two contrarian words,
work and failure.
We've been taught all of our lives to
not be a failure.
So, why am I standing here wishing you
embrace failing?
Avoiding failure is not the same as
achieving success.
In fact, finding failure is a discovery
of sorts.
It's a discovery of yet another way how
not to do something.
Failure is often on the path to success.
It was for Nvidia.
Nvidia fell failed from the very
beginning.
We found fame early on as a failed
startup
that was surely to go out of business.
You know, every high-tech startup
has a fundamental technology that they
thought they discovered.
And the fundamental technology we
founded the company on was a rendering
technology called forward texture
mapping. It doesn't matter what it
stands for. It doesn't matter what it
means.
There are tens of 3D There were tens of
3D graphics companies, huge established
ones like Silicon Graphics,
to well-funded startups like 3dfx.
And we were the only company to use this
approach.
We did it for logical reasons.
We believed in what we believed.
Well, our approach was flawed.
Inversed, which is the exact opposite,
rather than forward, was the better
solution.
We were just wrong.
After 2 million 2 years and millions of
dollars later, we had to change our
course. We failed.
Now, how could anything good come from
being completely wrong, from being a
complete failure? Well, it turns out
because we were so different
and didn't work with standards, we had
to evangelize our unique architecture
directly to software developers and game
developers.
And in working with the game creators,
we adopted their sensibility.
The tech that technology matters,
but it's really about fun and beautiful
imageries.
We learned that we were not just a chip
or a technology company.
Nvidia was really a company at the
intersection of technology and art.
So, even after we changed course and
became the world's last
among many 3D companies,
all using inverse texture mapping, we
retained that sensibility that games is
an art form.
And that we need to create technologies
that allow the game game developers to
artistically express their imagination.
And that purpose wasn't just to build a
chip, but to create an experience that
was magical and delightful.
This perspective led to fundamental
differences in how we approached our
work and led to many inventions
that changed the computer industry
altogether.
Today, Nvidia's the largest and the only
dedicated visual computing company in
the world, the most successful computer
graphics company in history. And that
sensibility permeates our company to
this day.
It all started because we chose the
wrong technology.
Because we failed.
So, my second wish to you is embrace
failure.
My last two last wish to you is to see
the world like a child.
You know, certainly after all this
education, and we've been told to grow
up to grow up, uh I'm giving you yet
another contrarian advice.
Another wish to see the world like a
child. To see the world without
preconceived notions and prejudice.
The world is complex. You're going to go
into a complicated world. Sometimes
rather cynical.
We are surrounded by conventional wisdom
dictating that what works and what
doesn't.
It is true.
Most ideas simply won't work.
We created one that didn't.
So, you must rigorously test your ideas
against first principles, those first
principles you've been taught here.
But then believe in what you believe.
It's up to all the
If up to all the customers, industry
analysts, other companies in the
computer industry, Nvidia shouldn't even
be here today.
We were already dead last among many.
The world surely didn't need yet another
PC graphics company, and the space was
littered with tens of competitors
leapfrogging each other every month.
All of the conventional wisdom
was true historically,
but we believed completely irrelevant to
the future that we saw.
We believed that computer graphics was
to become a massive opportunity as
computing devices and displays
proliferate everywhere and surround us.
That the visual experience will become
central to how we use computers.
That generating realistic images on a
computer was incredibly hard and offered
years of innovation, and that great
graphics will come to define future
computers.
We were young, naive, idealistic.
We didn't know what we didn't know
about building the industry and about
building our company.
We didn't know that it was impossible.
We just imagined how great it would be
if computers
would do what we imagined.
Our fresh and innocent perspective
unencumbered by conventional wisdom
allows the allowed us to see
what 30, 40, 50 other companies
could not and did not.
To this day, we challenge conventional
wisdom with the same innocence.
I wish you my third wish to see the
world like a child.
Those are my three wishes to you: to
fall in love,
to enjoy failure,
and to challenge conventional wisdom by
seeing the world like a child.
I hope these wishes come true for you as
it has for me.
I hope you live a life of hopes
and bravely pursue
these hopes
your entire life.
Congratulations, class of 2009.
I hope suffering happens to you.
Run, don't walk.
I wish you success.